Guide to the Herbert Matter Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Series 4: Graphic Design Projects, 71.5 linear ft.
  - Subseries 4.23: Prints and Working Prints
    - Artwork of painted cat figure.ND, b/w print. (Othertype 435, Folder 10)
    - Woman's hand with bracelet and stopwatch.ND, b/w prints. (Othertype 435, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified mother and daughter in field.ND, b/w print. (Othertype 435, Folder 12)
    - Ethnic looking man with white beard in street.ND, b/w contact prints and prints. (Othertype 435, Folder 13)
    - Exteriors of houseBuilt by Henry and Susanne Schultz 1843.ND, b/w contact prints. (Othertype 435, Folder 14)
    - New York City skyline.ND, b/w reverse printed (negative). (Othertype 435, Folder 15)
    - Street view of Empire State Building; New York City; Christmas lights hanging on nearby building.ND, b/w reverse printed (negative). (Othertype 435, Folder 16)
    - Fox in zoo.ND, b/w prints. (Othertype 435, Folder 17)
    - New York City street scene with shipping dollies.ND, b/w prints. (Othertype 435, Folder 18)
    - Metal-cross members on grid.ND, b/w prints. (Othertype 435, Folder 19)
    - Jackson Pollock paintings., b/w prints: includes 1948 painting. (Othertype 435, Folder 20)
    - Shadows of glass objects on table.ND, b/w prints. (Othertype 435, Folder 21)
    - New York City brick-carrier.ND, b/w prints. (Othertype 435, Folder 22)
    - Industrial power lines; water dam.ND, b/w contact prints. (Othertype 435, Folder 23)
    - Multiple image with fashion model hands.ND, b/w photostat. (Othertype 435, Folder 24)
    - Bar interior; nautical theme.ND, b/w contact prints. (Othertype 435, Folder 25)
    - Unidentified man in suit with glasses at desk in office.ND, b/w contact prints and prints. (Othertype 435, Folder 26)
    - Unidentified woman standing with veil on back of head and sitting in Eames chair prototype.ND, b/w contact prints. (Othertype 435, Folder 27)
    - Unidentified man with glasses; tie; and reclinging.ND, b/w prints. (Othertype 435, Folder 28)
    - Coal.ND, b/w prints. (Othertype 435, Folder 29)
    - Unidentified couple in various poses.ND, b/w contact prints and prints. (Othertype 435, Folder 30)
    - Unidentified woman in various poses (informal).ND, b/w contact prints. (Othertype 435, Folder 31)
    - Unidentified man with dark hair in suit.ND, b/w contact prints. (Othertype 435, Folder 32)
- Series 5: Non-Commercial Projects, 74.5 linear ft.
  This series represents Matter's personal and creative photography. The majority of the material in this series relates to Matter's photography of sculptor Alberto Giacometti and his work during the 1960s and 1970s. Contains extensive production materials involved in the publication of Matter's book: Alberto Giacometti; text by Mercedes Matter; foreword by Louis Finkelstein; with an introduction by Andrew Forge. New York: Abrams, 1987. Series includes negatives, and prints of Giacometti, abstracts, nudes (Mercedes Matter, Provincetown, MA. 1940), Brazil, Native Americans (New Mexico), East Indian Dancers (Pravina and others), and Alexander Calder. In addition to experimental, and assorted non-commerical works.
  - Subseries 5.01: Prints
    - Subsubseries 5.01.01: Nudes (Mercedes Matter)
      - "Mercedes Matter; Provincetown, MA; 1940; [Folder 1 of 2].1940 ca., b/w 8"x10": 11"x14" prints includes 2 1/4" contact prints. (Othertype 426)
      - "Mercedes Matter; Provincetown, MA; 1940; [Folder 2 of 2]."1940 ca., b/w 2 1/4" contact prints mounted on board. (Othertype 426)
    - Subsubseries 5.01.02: Landscapes, Seascapes, and Nature
      - Forest; snowdrift; wagonwheels; rocks., b/w prints. (Box 139, Folder 1)
      - Bethlehem with icicles., b/w prints. (Box 139, Folder 2)
      - Stone walls., b/w prints. (Box 139, Folder 3)
      - Townscape; asphalt., b/w prints. (Box 139, Folder 4)
      - Broken down tree; house; rocks; pear tree., b/w prints. (Box 139, Folder 5)
      - Ice on bark; trees in fog., b/w prints. (Box 139, Folder 6)
      - Bark., b/w prints. (Box 139, Folder 7)
      - Old and new tree., b/w prints. (Box 139, Folder 8)
      - Rocks; Switzerland; cows; woodpile; Trulsee; [1 of 2]., b/w prints. (Box 139, Folder 9)
      - Ice on trees; shrub., b/w prints. (Box 139, Folder 10)
      - "Winter '79 ("very cold"). ", b/w prints. (Box 139, Folder 11)
      - Roots; tree stem; squirrel; plant delicate., b/w prints. (Box 139, Folder 12)
      - Feathers., b/w prints. (Box 139, Folder 13)
      - For a rainy day (umbrellas)., b/w prints. (Box 139, Folder 14)
      - Composition with linens; fruits; eggs; limes., b/w prints. (Box 139, Folder 15)
      - Cows., b/w prints. (Box 139, Folder 16)
      - Rocks; Switzerland; cows; woodpile; Trulsee; [2 of 2]., b/w prints. (Box 139, Folder 17)
      - Unidentified jelly-like sea creature; [Box 1 of 2]., b/w 2 1/4" contact sheet. (Othertype 240, Folder 5)
      - Trees; ice in winter; metal door handle; [Box 1 of 2]., b/w 2 1/4" contact sheet. (Othertype 240, Folder 6)
      - Beach; rocks; shells; [Box 2 of 2]., b/w 2 1/4" contact sheet. (Othertype 263, Folder 2)
      - Winter trees; mountains; sky with lake in background.ND, b/w prints. (Othertype 437, Folder 1)
      - "Cows; rocks; water; Gaspe, Canada."ND, b/w print: enlarged contact print from 35mm negatives (Othertype 437, Folder 2)
      - "Seagulls; Gaspe, Canada."ND, b/w various sizes. (Othertype 437, Folder 3)
      - Includes Canada and other locations.ND, b/w prints. (Othertype 437, Folder 4)
      - "Boats, waterscapes; Canada."ND, b/w prints. (Othertype 437, Folder 5)
      - "Landscapes, city buildings; Canada."ND, b/w prints: 2 1/4" contact prints: Includes contact prints mounted on board. (Othertype 437, Folder 6)
      - Rocks. Includes Canada. ND, b/w prints. (Othertype 437, Folder 7)
      - "Gaspe, Canada. Portraits of residents."ND, b/w prints. (Othertype 437, Folder 8)
    - Subsubseries 5.01.03: Brazil, MINA book project
      - Mina. ND, Prints: layouts on board: transparencies: clippings. (Othertype 221, Folder 1)
      - Mina [Box 1 of 2]., b/w 2 1/4" contact sheets. (Othertype 240, Folder 4)
    - Subsubseries 5.01.04: Native Americans (New Mexico)
      - Native Americans (oversized). ND, b/w prints and 2 1/4" prints mounted on cardboard. (Othertype 221, Folder 4)
      - Native Americans (New Mexico). [Box 2 of 2]., b/w 2 1/4" contact prints. (Othertype 263, Folder 1)
    - Subsubseries 5.01.05: East Indian Dancers
      - Dancers., b/w prints (Othertype 133)
        Pravina
      - Dancers., b/w 8"x10" prints" (Box 134)
      - Contact Prints; [Box 1 of 2]., b/w 4"x5" prints. (Othertype 137, Folder 1)
      - Contact Prints; [Box 1 of 2]., b/w 35 mm prints. (Othertype 137, Folder 2)
      - Contact Prints; (Not Pravina) [Box 1 of 2]., b/w 8"x10": 2 1/4" prints. (Othertype 137, Folder 3)
      - Nehru's nieces; [Box 2 of 2]., b/w contact prints: 8"x10": 11'x14" prints. (Othertype 262, Folder 4)
      - East Indian dancers and includes boy.ND, b/w contact prints: 2 1/4": 4"x5": 8"x10". (Othertype 409)
        Relates to Pravina
    - Subsubseries 5.01.06: Assorted Work
      - New Bauhaus; ND, b/w 2 1/4": 8"x10" contact prints. (Othertype 221, Folder 2)
        "Walter Gropius, Laszlo Moholy Nagy, James Johnson Sweeney, Archipenko. "
      - Unidentified woman with light drawing on face; Related to gifted print# 36105115667482.ND, b/w prints. (Othertype 439, Folder 1)
      - Mary Barnes sitting on floor with rope.ND, b/w print. (Othertype 439, Folder 2)
      - "Deer Island, Maine; medium size black dog on rocks with unidentified woman."ND, b/w contact prints. (Othertype 439, Folder 3)
      - "Deer Island, Maine; small black dog."ND, b/w print. (Othertype 439, Folder 4)
    - Subsubseries 5.01.07: Unidentified Projects
      - "Gypsy Girl, 1929". [Box 1 of 2].", b/w 4"x5" contact print. (Othertype 240, Folder 7)
    - Subsubseries 5.01.08: Working Prints
      - Abstracts.ND, b/w cut-outs. (Othertype 221, Folder 3)
      - Assorted prints [1 of 2].ND, various size prints (Othertype 221, Folder 4)
      - Assorted prints [2 of 2].ND, various size prints (Othertype 221, Folder 5)
      - Bread (Close-up).ND, b/w various sizes. (Othertype 221, Folder 6)
      - Ink and water abstract.ND, b/w various sizes. (Othertype 221, Folder 7)
      - Canada; People; houses; buildings; animalsND, b/w 2 1/4" contact print strips mounted on board " (Othertype 300)
      - Large graphic eye.ND, b/w print. (Othertype 431)
      - Herbert Matter's handprints.ND, b/w photostat and print. (Othertype 431)
      - Photograms (tools; nails; scissors).ND, b/w various sizes: photograms. (Othertype 431)
      - Portrait of young girl with long light colored hair.ND, b/w contact prints and prints. (Othertype 431)
      - Abstract forms.ND, b/w various sizes. (Othertype 431)
      - "Solarized cabbage, 1943."1943 ca., b/w various sizes. (Othertype 431)
      - Bare trees with water in background.ND, b/w contact prints. (Othertype 433, Folder 1)
      - Wood on Jackson Pollock property.ND, b/w contact prints. (Othertype 433, Folder 2)
      - "Trees with snow, frost, and ice."ND, b/w prints. (Othertype 433, Folder 3)
      - Bethlehem house during winter time.ND, b/w contact prints and prints. (Othertype 433, Folder 4)
      - Static electricity; electrical discharge emulsion.ca. 1943, b/w print. (Othertype 433, Folder 5)
      - Horses.ND, b/w print: enlarged contact print from 35mm negatives. (Othertype 433, Folder 6)
      - Turkeys; horses.ND, b/w print: enlarged contact print from 35mm negatives. (Othertype 433, Folder 7)
      - Yale students; downtown construction; broken windows; trees.ND, b/w print: enlarged contact print from 35mm negatives. (Othertype 433, Folder 8)
      - Fire and flames.ND, b/w prints. (Othertype 433, Folder 9)
      - "Sunshine Island, Maine."ND, b/w prints. (Othertype 433, Folder 10)
      - "Composition, 1943"1943 ca., b/w contact prints: print. (Othertype 433, Folder 11)
      - Mercedes Matter wearing coral in hair.ND, b/w print. (Othertype 433, Folder 12)
      - Wood shavings.ND, b/w contact prints. (Othertype 433, Folder 13)
      - Two young South African men with baskets on their heads.ND, b/w contact prints. (Othertype 433, Folder 14)
  - Subseries 5.02: Alberto Giacometti Book
    - Subsubseries 5.02.01: Book Process
      - Photostats. (Othertype 28)
        "Paintings, drawings, portraits, interiors, exteriors, sculptures"
      - Book Process; Artwork, Layouts (Othertype 57)
        "Layout storyboard with small Photostats, Layout possibilities includes photographs. Artwork is material used in production, layout, design of book."
      - Manuscript drawings and sketches by Matter., pencil: pen and colored pencil on paper (Othertype 73)
      - Manuscript by Matter., typed and handwritten: including notes (Othertype 74)
      - Book Process; Artwork. (Othertype 76)
        "Not used in Giacometti Book. Artwork is material used in production, layout, design of book, generally includes photographs and notations."
      - Book Process; Maquette. (Othertype 78)
      - Book Process; Artwork. (Othertype 86)
        "Jacket, cover, pages 2-5, 15-25, 27-49, Photographs, layout annotations. Artwork is material used in production, layout, design of book."
      - Book Process; Artwork. (Othertype 87)
        "Pages 50-53, 58-59, 61-63, 65-91, 94-101, 50-53, 58-59, 61-63, 65-91, 94-101, Photographs, layout annotations. Artwork is material used in production, layout, design of book."
      - Book Process; Artwork. (Othertype 88)
        "Pages 102, 105, 106, 109-112, 114-126, 128-134, 136, 138-168, 170-175, 177, 179, 181, 183-193, 102, 105, 106, 109-112, 114-126, 128-134, 136, 138-168, 170-175, 177, 179, 181, 183-193, Photographs, layout annotations. Artwork is material used in production, layout, design of book."
      - Book Process; Artwork., Lettering: title layout (Oversize 89)
        "Artwork is material used in production, layout, design of book."
      - Book Process; Artwork., Lettering: title layout (Othertype 90)
        "Includes layouts, drawings, cut paste objects. Artwork is material used in production, layout, design of book."
      - Book Process; Artwork., Layouts and notes for text: credits (various editions) (Othertype 91)
      - Book Process; Notes; layout dimensions; calculations. (Othertype 93)
        "Calculations for print size, page size, book structure, notes related to book production, schedule, calendar 1960, 1975, 1977."
      - Book Process; Manuscript., typed (Othertype 94)
        by Mercedes Matter.
        "Matter, Mercedes;"
      - Book Process; Manuscript., typed (Othertype 95)
      - Book Process; Manuscript., typed (Othertype 96)
      - Book Process; Manuscript., typed (Othertype 97)
      - Book Process; Manuscript., handwritten (Othertype 98)
      - Book Process; Manuscript., handwritten (Othertype 99)
      - Book Process; Manuscript., handwritten (Othertype 100)
      - Book Process; Manuscript., translations to/from French by Mercedes Matter (Othertype 101)
      - Book Process; Manuscript [1 of 2] English., photocopies in French and English: typed (Othertype 102, Folder 1)
        Contains reduced size photocopy of book
      - Book Process; Manuscript [2 of 2] English., photocopies in French and English: typed (Othertype 102, Folder 2)
      - Book Process; Manuscript [1 of 6]French., photocopies in French and English: typed (Othertype 102, Folder 3)
        Contains reduced size photocopy of book.
      - Book Process; Manuscript [2 of 6] French., photocopies in French and English: typed (Othertype 102, Folder 4)
      - Book Process; Manuscript [3 of 6] French., photocopies in French and English: typed (Othertype 102, Folder 5)
      - Book Process; Manuscript [4 of 6] French., photocopies in French and English: typed (Othertype 102, Folder 6)
      - Book Process; Manuscript [5 of 6] French., photocopies in French and English: typed (Othertype 102, Folder 7)
      - Book Process; Manuscript [6 of 6] French., photocopies in French and English: typed (Othertype 102, Folder 8)
      - Book Process; Manuscript. (Othertype 103)
        "by Annette Giacometti, David Sylvester, Isaku Yanaihara, Manuscript by Annette Giacometti, typed (French), Manuscript by David Sylvester, Manuscript by Isaku Yanaihara.
        Giacometti, Annette; Sylvester, David; Yanaihara, Isaku
      - Book Process; Manuscript., typed (Othertype 104)
        related to Isaku Yanaihara.
        "Yanaihara, Isaku "
      - Book Process; Press Proofs. (Othertype 105)
      - Book Process; Press Proofs. (Othertype 106)
      - Book Process; Press Releases; addresses; travel receipts., Press Releases: Book Exhibition: Addresses: Travel receipts (Othertype 111)
    - Subsubseries 5.02.02: Clippings
      - Book Process; Clippings [1 of 4] English., Photocopies English: French: German (Othertype 112, Folder 1)
      - Book Process; Clippings [2 of 4] English., Photocopies English: French: German (Othertype 112, Folder 2)
      - Book Process; Clippings [3 of 4] English., Photocopies English: French: German (Othertype 112, Folder 3)
      - Book Process; Clippings [4 of 4] English., Photocopies English: French: German (Othertype 112, Folder 4)
      - Book Process; Clippings [1 of 3] French., Photocopies English: French: German (Othertype 112, Folder 5)
      - Book Process; Clippings [2 of 3] French., Photocopies English: French: German (Othertype 112, Folder 6)
      - Book Process; Clippings [3 of 3] French., Photocopies English: French: German (Othertype 112, Folder 7)
      - Book Process; Clippings., Newspapers: magazines (Othertype 113)
    - Subsubseries 5.02.03: Contact Sheets
      - "Contact Prints; b/w 2 1/4" Archival Set.", numbered 545-620; Contact Prints; b/w 2 1/4" (Box 56)
      - "Contact Prints; b/w 2 1/4" Archival Set.", Contact Prints; b/w 2 1/4" Archival Set " (Box 57)
        numbered 621-687.
      - "Contact Prints; b/w 2 1/4" Sculptures.", Contact Prints; b/w 2 1/4" Sculptures" (Box 58)
      - "Contact Prints; b/w 2 1/4" Paintings; drawings; interiors; exteriors.", Contact Prints; b/w 2 1/4" (Othertype 59)
      - "Contact Prints; b/w 2 1/4" Archival Set.", Contact Prints; b/w 2 1/4". (Othertype 60)
        "numbered 51, 52, 55-90 Sculptures"
      - "Contact Prints; b/w 2 1/4" Archival Set.", Contact Prints; b/w 2 1/4". (Othertype 61)
        "Includes b/w 35mm contact prints of Yanaihara and Giacometti. Numbered 91-111, 121-130 Portraits, Giacometti, Isaku Yanaihara, Diego Giacometti"
        "Giacometti, Alberto; Yanaihara, Isaku; Giacometti, Diego
      - "Contact Prints; b/w 2 1/4".", Contact Prints; b/w 2 1/4". (Othertype 62)
        "Portrait Giacometti, Isaku Yanaihara, Diego Giacometti, Includes b/w 35mm contacts of Isaku Yanaihara, Diego Giacometti. Pierre Matisse with Herbert Matter."
      - "Contact Prints; b/w 4"x5" Exhibitions.", Contact Prints; b/w 4"x5" (Othertype 63)
      - "Contact Prints; b/w 8"x10" Paintings; drawings.", Contact Prints; b/w 8"x10" (Othertype 64)
      - "Contact Prints; b/w 8"x10" Paintings; drawings.", Contact Prints; b/w 8"x10" (Othertype 65)
      - "Contact Prints; b/w 8"x10" Paintings; drawings.", Contact Prints; b/w 8"x10" (Othertype 66)
      - "Contact Prints; b/w 8"x10" Sculptures.", Contact Prints; b/w 8"x10" (Othertype 67)
      - "Contact Prints; b/w 8"x10" Sculptures.", Contact Prints; b/w 8"x10" (Othertype 68)
      - "Contact Prints; b/w 8"x10" Sculptures.", Contact Prints; b/w 8"x10" (Othertype 69)
      - "Contact Prints; b/w 8"x10" Sculptures.", Contact Prints; b/w 8"x10" (Othertype 70)
      - Contact Prints; b/w 120mm mounted boards. (Othertype 71)
        Giacometti Portraits
        "Giacometti, Alberto;"
      - "Contact Prints; b/w 2 1/4"; 120mm; 2 3/4" mounted boards ." (Othertype 72)
    - Subsubseries 5.02.04: Correspondence
      - Correspondence. (Othertype 55)
        From Giacometti.
      - Book Process; Correspondence. (Othertype 75)
      - Book Process; Correspondence From Annette Giacometti; From Abrams Publishing; From Basilius Press; From BVD Publishing; From Isidore Cohen; To/From Isaku Yanaihara; To/From Assorted; Yale; Museum of Modern Art (MoMA); Galerie le chat Bernard; Druck and Verlagshaus; Galerie Maeght; Stiftung fur die Photographie; Norman Ives; Helvetica Press; Inc.; Assorted addresses. (Othertype 110)
    - Subsubseries 5.02.05: Exhibition Materials
      - Exhibitions; Artwork. (Othertype 52)
      - Exhibitions; Posters Guggenheim 1974 [1 of 2]. (Othertype 80)
        Guggenheim Museum
      - Exhibitions; Posters Guggenheim [2 of 2]. (Othertype 81)
        Layouts
      - Exhibitions; Posters German 1966. (Othertype 82)
      - Exhibitions; Posters Tate Gallery. (Othertype 83)
        Tate Gallery
      - Exhibitions; Posters Sterlip Press. (Othertype 84)
        Sterlip Press Promotional Poster
    - Subsubseries 5.02.06: Ives-Sillman
      - Book Process; THIRTEEN PHOTOGRAPHS - Ives Sillman. (Othertype 77)
      - Book Process; Ives Sillman portofolio production. (Othertype 79)
      - Book Process; Ives Sillman [1 of 5]. (Othertype 85, Folder 1)
        Includes press proof.
      - Book Process; Ives Sillman [2 of 5]. (Othertype 85, Folder 2)
      - Book Process; Ives Sillman [3 of 5]. (Othertype 85, Folder 3)
      - Book Process; Ives Sillman [4 of 5]. (Othertype 85, Folder 4)
      - Book Process; Ives Sillman [5 of 5]. (Othertype 85, Folder 5)
    - Subsubseries 5.02.07: Photographic Prints
      - "Photographs, Sculptures, Mountains; Cut prints.", Large prints. (Othertype 1)
      - Photographs; Sculptures; Cut prints., Small prints. (Oversize 2)
        "Paintings, Drawings, interiors, exteriors"
      - Photographs; Sculptures Cut prints [1 of 7]., Small prints (Oversize 2, Folder 1)
      - Photographs; Sculptures Cut prints [2 of 7]., Small prints (Oversize 2, Folder 2)
      - Photographs; Sculptures Cut prints [3 of 7]., Small prints (Oversize 2, Folder 3)
      - Photographs; Sculptures Cut prints [4 of 7]., Small prints (Oversize 2, Folder 4)
      - Photographs; Sculptures Cut prints [5 of 7]., Small prints (Oversize 2, Folder 5)
      - Photographs; Sculptures Cut prints [6 of 7]., Small prints (Oversize 2, Folder 6)
      - Photographs; Sculptures Cut prints [7 of 7]., Small prints (Oversize 2, Folder 7)
      - Photographs; Sculptures. (Othertype 3)
      - Photographs; Sculptures.ND (Othertype 4)
        "Portraits Giacometti, Diego Giacometti"
        "Giacometti, Alberto; Giacometti, Diego;"
      - Photographs; Sculptures. (Othertype 5)
      - Exterior studio. (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Exteriors. (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Exteriors. (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Interiors. (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Interiors. (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Exhibitions. (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Exhibitions. (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Photographs; Sculptures. (Othertype 7)
      - Photographs; Sculptures. (Othertype 8)
        "Color exteriors, paintings, drawings"
      - Photographs; Sculptures. (Othertype 9)
      - Photographs; Sculptures. (Othertype 10)
      - Photographs; Paintings; drawings. (Othertype 11)
      - Photographs; Sculptures. (Othertype 12)
      - Photographs; Sculptures. (Othertype 13)
      - Photographs; Sculptures. (Othertype 14)
      - Photographs; Sculptures. (Othertype 15)
      - Photographs; Portraits. (Othertype 16)
        Includes Isaku Yanaihara
        "Yanaihara, Isaku ;"
      - Photographs; Paintings; drawings. (Othertype 17)
      - Photographs; Paintings; drawings. (Othertype 18)
      - Photographs; Portraits. (Othertype 19)
      - Photographs; Sculptures. (Othertype 20)
      - Photographs; Exteriors. (Othertype 21)
      - Photographs; Paintings; drawings. (Othertype 22)
      - Photographs; Paintings; drawings. (Othertype 23)
      - Photographs; Sculptures. (Othertype 24)
      - Photographs; Sculptures. (Othertype 25)
      - Photographs; Sculptures. (Othertype 26)
      - Photographs; Interiors; exteriors. (Othertype 27)
    - Subsubseries 5.02.08: Reference File
      - Book Process; Reference material; photographs not by Matter. (Othertype 109)
      - Book Process; Reference material., Pages from publications (Othertype 114)
      - Book Process; Reference material., Exhibitions: announcements related to Matter: Includes exhibition announcements not related to Matter photography (Box 115)
    - Subsubseries 5.02.09: Slides
      - Slides., Color mounted Davidson brand metal frames and card mounted (Box 29, Folder 1)
        "Sculptures, exteriors, paintings, drawings"
      - Slides., Color mounted Davidson brand metal frames (Box 29, Folder 1)
        "Sculptures, exteriors"
      - Slides., Color: card mounted (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - Slides., Color 35mm (Othertype 30, Folder 1)
        "Portraits, paintings, drawings, interiors, exteriors"
      - Slides., Color 35mm (Othertype 30, Folder 1)
        portraits
      - Slides., Color 35mm (Othertype 30, Folder 2)
        "paintings, drawings"
      - Slides., Color 35mm (Othertype 30, Folder 3)
        "interiors, exteriors"
      - Slides., Color 35mm (Othertype 30, Folder 4)
        sculptures
    - Subsubseries 5.02.10: Transparencies
      - "Transparancy; Color 8"x10" Sculptures 1 of 3.", Transparancy; Color 8"x10" " (Othertype 31)
      - "Transparancy; Color 8"x10" Sculptures 2 of 3.", Transparancy; Color 8"x10" " (Othertype 32)
      - "Transparancy; Color 8"x10" Sculptures 3 of 3.", Transparancy; Color 8"x10" " (Othertype 33)
      - "Transparancy; b/w 8"x10" Sculptures.", Transparancy; b/w 8"x10" (Othertype 34)
      - "Transparancy; b/w 8"x10" Sculptures." (Othertype 35, Folder 1)
        "Paintings, drawings (labeled with numbers) B-15 to B-22, B-25 to B -28
      - "Transparancy; b/w 8"x10" Sculptures." (Othertype 35, Folder 2)
        "Paintings, drawings (labeled with numbers) B-29 to B-32, B-34 to B -37"